[SOUND]
[声音]
So, if we create stacked graph layouts,
如果我们为很多的因变量
stacked bar charts, and stacked line graphs of a lot of dependent variables,
创建堆叠的图形布局 堆叠的柱状图 以及堆叠的线状图
then you get some interesting effects as displayed here.
那么 你会看到一些有趣的效果 如同显示在这里一样
You start to see kind of a stream effect, and you can see the same
你开始看到好似水流的现象 并且你会看到同样的数据变量
data variable evolving as it moves across the horizontal axis.
沿着水平坐标轴而变化
But you also see some other problems with this representation.
但你也看到这一表现方式 的一些其它的问题
One is that the variants in the lower variables
其一是 堆叠在较下层的变量的变化
in the stack can influence the shape of the higher variables.
会影响上层变量的形状
And it can be harder to see when things get sheared towards the outsides,
这样叠加到外层 就更难看出
whether they're representing the variables the same value or if it's increasing or
它们展示的变量是相同值 还是变量的值在增大还是
decreasing.
是在减小。
And also you can see that by the time you get to the very top of the graph,
而且 你会看到 当到达图的最顶层时
it's changing quite violently because it's the sum of all the changes that have
它的变化更显著 因为那是所有发生在其下层的
happened below it.
变化的总和
We can analyze this by using a few variables.
我们可以用少许几个变量 来分析这一现象
If we let each variable at a given horizontal position on the horizontal
假使我们在横轴上每一指定的位置 赋予一个变量
axis, each variable be represented by say, f1 for the first variable,
每一个变量被表示为 比如说 f1 代表第一个变量
f2 for the second variable And so on, f1, f2, f3.
f2 代表第二个变量 以此类推 f1 f2 f3 等
Then we can define, basically, ground zero, g0, to be the baseline level.
然后 我们可以定义 起始零值 g0 做为基线
And in this case, we're just setting g0 to be 0, just at the horizontal axis.
在这个例子中 我们简单地令 g0 等于零 即位于横轴上
Then g i is the position of the top of the plot of the i'th variable.
那么 gi 就是第 i 个变量 的图线顶端的位置
And the top of the plot of the i'th variable g i is just equal to g0
第 i 个变量的图线顶端 gi 正好等于 g0 加上
plus that variable and all the variables below it in the stack.
第 i 个变量以及堆叠在其下 所有的变量之和
And we can start to do some analysis.
我们可以开始做一些分析
And because of this analysis, there is an alternative layout called ThemeRiver.
正因为这一分析 有了另一种 展示方式 被称为主题河流（ThemeRiver）
And ThemeRiver basically centered the vertical plot,
总的来说 主题河流是将 竖直方向的图线沿中心对齐
the stack of variables along the horizontal axis.
即中心对齐横轴延伸
Set it set g0 to be one-half of the total height of the stack of variables.
就是将 g0 设置在堆叠后所有变量的 总高度一半的位置
And by doing that, it basically said that the way this thing is varying at the top
通过这样做 基本上可以说 图线在预层变化的样子
will be a mirror image of the way this thing is varying at the bottom.
将会是图线在底层 变化样子的一个镜像
And you get more of a, the appearance of a river that data is kind of streaming by
你得到的看起来更像一条河流 数据在流动变化
and evolving and it reduced the amount of shearing that was happening,
这样减小了前面所说的剪切现象
but it didn't eliminate it completely.
但并没有完全去除它
You can see for example, this region right here, is creating a large
例如 你可以看到这个区域 在其数据周围
shift in the data around it that you'd like to be able to minimize.
产生了一个很大的偏移 你是希望把这种影响减到最小化的
So just by centering the vertical stack of data around the horizontal axis
所以 仅仅沿横轴中心对齐 垂直方向堆叠的数据
minimizes the heighth of the chart around
就减小了图线沿横轴的高度
that horizontal axis and it also minimizes the slope at the top and the bottom.
而且 还减小了 顶部和底部的倾斜程度
There's a Streamgraph layout that does an even better job of this and
有一种流形图（Streamgraph）方式 在这方面做的更好
it does this just by changing where the position g0 is.
它是通过改变 g0 点位置 来实现的
Streamgraph sets g0 equal to the result of this formula.
流形图令根据这个图中的公式 来设置 g0 的位置
So you just evaluate this formula based on your data values f i,
即基于数据值 fi 按该公式计算 g0
and we won't go through the derivation of this formula.
我们不会详细讲解 这一公式的推导
But by just changing where the base of this stacked bar chart or
通过改变堆叠柱状图 或者堆叠线状图
stacked line chart occurs and then stacking based to that new baseline,
的基准位置 再基于这一新的基线进行堆叠
we get an even smoother appearance and it makes it even easier for
我们得到一个更佳平滑的图形 并且让我们
us to make comparisons as we move horizontally across this chart,
在沿水平方向看这个图的时候 更容易进行比较
to determine relative changes to each of these dependent variables.
以确定这些因变量的相对变化
It minimizes the deviation and the wiggle, the deviation being how far
它减小了偏差以及摆动 偏差是指一个变量画出来
a variable's plot moves from its previous position on the horizontal axis,
在横轴方向上从它之前的位置 移动了多远
and the wiggle is minimizing the slope, basically the sheer effect
摆动是减小了斜率 即 剪切效应
that you get from the wiggle.
就是由摆动而产生的
You can also improve the appearance by changing the order in which you
你还可以改进其形状 通过改变你叠加变量
add variables.
的顺序
So, if variables are zero until a certain position on the horizontal axis,
所以 如果一些变量在横轴上 某个位置之前都是零
and then they change from zero to some value,
之后从零变为其它值
you can change where they appear in the stack of variables.
你可以改变它们在变量 堆叠的什么地方显示
And so in this case, they're just stacked in some fixed ordering,
在上面这种情况下 它们 以某种固定的
some arbitrary ordering.
随意的顺序堆叠在一起
And you can see kind of a stream in the coloring.
你可以看到有点儿 像是一个着色的水流
Coloring each variable differently helps perceive that stream.
给每一个变零用不同的着色 有助于感知那个水流
In this case they're colored based on when the variable
在下面这个例子中 它们的着色是基于变量
starts to take on a value other than zero.
什么时候有非零值开始
But you can also add new variables
但是 你也可以增加新的变量
when the variables take on a value other than zero.
当这些变量取非零值的时候
You can always add them to the outside of the graph.
你可以一直吧它们加到 这个图的外侧
And what that does, is it takes variables that start out
具体是这样 当变量开始
at a certain point on the horizontal axis, as soon as they take on the nonzero value,
在横轴某个特定位置 取到非零值时
you add them but you add them to the outside, so
你就把它们加在图上的外侧
their initial surge in value doesn't disturb the other variables.
这样其取值的突然增大 不会扰乱其它的变量
It's happening on the outside of the graph.
因为它是加在图的外侧
And then as it's waning, other variables
之后 随着它的衰减 其它变量
are taking non-zero values and being added to the outside of the graph.
也从零变为非零值 并被加到图的外侧
And so you get this nice, flowing appearance where you can see the relative
于是 你得到这种漂亮的图形
change in values of these variables as you move right on the horizontal axis,
你可看到变量沿着横轴向右的 相对变化
even though we're looking at 10 or 20 variables in a given stack, vertically.
即使我们在看的是垂直方向有 10个或者20个变量在一个堆叠图里
So we learned how to make a stream graph, and
至此 我们学习了如何创建一个流形图 以及
how something as simple as stacking a bar chart can become
象把柱状图堆叠起来 这样简单的事情如何能成为
a point of further investigation in order to how to display it effectively.
将来可被进一步探究于 如何有效用于显示
We also learned that, for example,
我们还学到 例如
a pie chart can become misleading especially when shown in three dimensions.
一个饼状图会产生误导 特别是在三维中显示的时候
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community